I currently work as a Software Engineer for Casey's General Stores in Ankeny and have been since March 2019.

I utilize SQL, C#, and LINQ to create .NET MVC web applications and REST APIs that help Casey's better serve its customers.

I graduated from the University of Northern Iowa with a bachelor's degree in Management Information Systems in May of 2016. I also graduated in 2012 with an associate degree as a Computer Support Specialist.

View my portfolio at www.benjaminsampica.com.

Employment History

03/2019 - Present

Casey's General Stores Ankeny, Iowa

Software Engineer

- Spearheading efforts to convert legacy Casey's applications to smaller, consumable RESTful APIs using ASP.NET Core, Swagger, and Mulesoft.
- Building new web applications with ASP.NET Core to support Casey's growing need for mobile/portable applications.
- Utilize Agile processes like sprints, team backlog grooming sessions, story points, and scrum boards through Azure DevOps.
- Setup and manage CI/CD pipelines for existing legacy applications and new applications inside of Azure DevOps.
- Maintain legacy Casey's applications, primarily in VBScript and VB.NET.

06/2016 - 03/2019

Polk County Des Moines, Iowa

Web Application Developer

- Full-stack development starting with gathering requirements/existing workflows through frontend implementation with client acceptance.
- Used cloud source control (Bitbucket w/ Sourcetree) and peer code review for all development.
- Utilized Agile processes like sprints, team backlog grooming sessions, story points, and scrum boards (JIRA).
- Continuous Improvement through upgrading projects from MVC4/MVC5 to MVC 6 when time/necessity allowed.
- Extended Bootstrap 3 and 4 with custom CSS/JS solutions to match client needs.
- Created and actively developed/maintained Polk County's web-based staff scheduler program. This included calculating and tracking accruals, scheduling hours, exporting payroll, scheduling employee time off as well as providing consumable, interactive calendar views for employees and supervisors alike among a laundry list of features.
- Created/actively developed a web-based case manager system for the Polk County Sheriff's Office which included dynamic document generation, geolocating and address retrieval through Google API, a double-entry accounting system, and e-filer with Selenium through the State of Iowa website for returns of service

01/2016 - 06/2016

The Members Group Urbandale, Iowa

IT Service Coordinator

- Took Help Desk Support calls and logged tickets.

- Resolved Tier 1 Tier 3 (Non-Application Development) tickets.
- Trained incoming Tier 1 employees on common issues and application-specific workflows.

05/2015 - 08/2015

Mercer Urbandale, Iowa

IT Intern

- Updated, created, and maintained company SharePoint sites.
- Led project to create a SharePoint consistency template among team sites.
- Created automation scripts with Selenium in Java for large-scale automation testing.
- Wrote documentation for SharePoint from both a users and developers point of view.
- Updated VBA-based software to improve search accuracy and added in new systems.

Professional Skills

✓ HTML

✓ MVC

✓ EF Core

✓ Bootstrap 4

✓ Bootstrap 3

✓ JIRA

✓ C#

✓ .NET

✓ LINQ

✓ EF 5

✓ Azure DevOps

✓ CSS

✓ Javascript

✓ Git

✓ MSSQL

Education

Management Information Systems

Graduated - 05/2016 • University of Northern Iowa Cedar Falls, Iowa Officer of UNIPAWWSH (charity group). Officer of UNISTARR (Student rights group).

Computer Support Specialist

Graduated - 12/2012 • Kirkwood Community College Cedar Rapids, Iowa